<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ballpointcarrot.net</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Orange, and goes 'click, click.'</description>
    <atom:link href="welcome-to-harp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Harp</title>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>This little posts will introduce you to Markdown in Harp. Go ahead and edit the <code>welcome-to-harp.md</code> file to get going and learn how it all works!</p>
<h2>Getting Started</h2><p>Writing in Markdown is really easy. Where appropriate, you can use <em>formatting</em> shortcuts to style your content. For example, a list:</p>
<ul>
<li>Item number one</li>
<li>Item number two<ul>
<li>A nested item</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A final item</li>
</ul>
<p>or with numbers!</p>
<ol>
<li>Remember to buy some milk</li>
<li>Drink the milk</li>
<li>Tweet that I remembered to buy the milk, and drank it</li>
</ol>
<h3>Links</h3><p>Want to link to a source? No problem. If you paste in url, like <a href="http://harpjs.com">http://harpjs.com</a> - it’ll automatically be linked up. But if you want to customise your anchor text, you can do that too! Here’s a link to <a href="http://harpjs.com">the Harp website</a>. Neat.</p>
<h3>What about Images?</h3><p>Images work too! Already know the URL of the image you want to include in your article? Simply paste it in like this to make it show up:</p>
<p><img src="http://harpjs.com/identity/resources/750/harp-wordmark-white-on-blue.png" alt="The Harp Logo"></p>
<p>Not sure which image you want to use yet? That’s ok too. Leave yourself a descriptive placeholder and keep writing.</p>
<p>![A bowl of bananas]</p>
<h3>Quoting</h3><p>Sometimes a link isn’t enough, you want to quote someone on what they’ve said. It was probably very wisdomous. Is wisdomous a word? Find out in a future release when we introduce spellcheck! For now – it’s definitely a word.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wisdomous – it’s definitely a word.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Working with Code</h3><p>Got a streak of geek? We’ve got you covered there, too. You can write inline <code>&lt;code&gt;</code> blocks really easily with back ticks. Want to show off something more comprehensive? Using <code>```</code> at the beginning and end of the block gets you there.</p>
<pre><code class="language-css">.awesome-thing {
    display: block;
    width: 100%;
}
</code></pre>
<h3>Ready for a Break?</h3><p>Throw 3 or more dashes down on any new line and you’ve got yourself a fancy new divider. Aw yeah.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Advanced Usage</h3><p>There’s one fantastic secret about Markdown. If you want, you can write plain old HTML and it&#39;ll still work! Very flexible.</p>
<input type="text" placeholder="I’m an input field!" />

<p>That should be enough to get you started with Markdown.</p>
<h2>Learn more about Harp</h2><p>Now, you’re probably read to start customising your static blog with Harp. Take a look at these helpful resources:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://harpjs.com/docs/quick-start">Harp quick start guide</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kennethormandy.com/journal/start-a-blog-with-harp">Start a blog with Harp blog post</a></li>
<li><a href="http://harpjs.com/docs/">The Harp documentation</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
        <pubDate>Sat Feb 28 2015 10:50:48 GMT-0800 (PST)</pubDate>
        <link>/welcome-to-harp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/welcome-to-harp</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>